[{"question":"1.Information to develop a project network is collected from the\nA.Organization breakdown structure\nB.Work breakdown structure\nC.Budget\nD.Project proposal\nE.Responsibility matrix","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"The network is developed from the information collected for the WBS and is a graphic flow chart of the projectjob plan.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"2.Which of the following represents an activity on an AON project network?\nA.An arrow\nB.A line\nC.A node\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The two approaches used to develop project networks are known as activity-on-node (AON) and activity-on-arrow(AOA). Both methods use two building blocks— the arrow and the node. Their names derive from the fact thatthe former uses a node to depict an activity.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"3.Arrows on an AON project network represent:\nA.An activity\nB.Project flow\nC.Dependency\nD.Both B and C are correct\nE.Both A and B are correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"The node depicts an activity, and the arrow shows dependency and project flow.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"4.When translated into a project network, a work package will become\nA.A single activity\nB.One or more activities\nC.A milestone\nD.A critical path\nE.An arrow","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Work packages from the WBS are used to build the activities found in the project network. An activity can includeone or more work packages. The activities are placed in a sequence that provides for orderly completion ofthe project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"5.Which of the following is provided by a project network but not by the work breakdown structure?\nA.Dependencies\nB.Sequencing\nC.Interrelationships\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Project networks are developed from the WBS. The project network is a visual flow diagram of the sequence, interrelationships,and dependencies of all the activities that must be accomplished to complete the project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"6.On a project network, the activity times are derived from the\nA.Organization breakdown structure\nB.Work packages\nC.Budget\nD.Project proposal\nE.Responsibility matrix","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Work packages from the WBS are used to build the activities found in the project network. An activity is an elementin the project that consumes time—for example, work or waiting.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"7.Part of a project is to \nDevelop Product Specifications. This is best classified as a(n)\nA.Event\nB.Path\nC.Activity\nD.Node\nE.Milestone","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Activities usually represent one or more tasks from a work package. Descriptions of activities should use a verb/noun","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"8.An activity that has more than one dependency arrow flowing into it is termed a(n)\nA.Parallel activity\nB.Critical path\nC.Burst activity\nD.Merge activity\nE.Independent activity","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Merge activity is an activity that has more than one activity immediately preceding it (more than one dependencyarrow flowing to it).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"9.The critical path in a project network is the\nA.Shortest path through the network\nB.Longest path through the network\nC.Network path with the most difficult activities\nD.Network path using the most resources\nE.Network path with the most merge activities","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"When this term is used, it means the path(s) with the longest duration through the network; if an activity onthe path is delayed, the project is delayed the same amount of time.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"10.A/an _________ activity has more than one dependency arrow flowing from it.\nA.Parallel\nB.Critical path\nC.Burst\nD.Merge\nE.Independent","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Burst activity is an activity has more than one activity immediately following it (more than one dependency arrowflowing from it).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"11.An item on a project network is \nDesign Software Completed. This is best described as a(n)\nA.Event\nB.Path\nC.Activity\nD.Node\nE.Milestone","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Event is a term used to represent a point in time when an activity is started or completed. It does not consumetime.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"12.Activities which can take place at the same time are termed\nA.Parallel activity\nB.Critical path\nC.Burst activity\nD.Merge activity\nE.Independent activity","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"These are activities that can take place at the same time, if the manager wishes. However, the manager may chooseto have parallel activities not occur simultaneously.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"13.A sequence of connected, dependent activities is termed a(n)\nA.Critical path\nB.Parallel path\nC.Activity chain\nD.Path\nE.Dependent chain","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"A Path is a sequence of connected, dependent activities.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"14.An AON project network uses which of the following basic building blocks?\nA.Arrows\nB.Bars\nC.Nodes\nD.Both A and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"The two approaches used to develop project networks are known as activity-on-node (AON) and activity-on-arrow(AOA). Both methods use two building blocks— the arrow and the node.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"15.Which of the following is not one of the basic rules to follow when developing project networks?\nA.An activity cannot begin until all preceding activities have been completed\nB.Each activity must have a unique identification number\nC.Conditional statements are allowed but looping statements are not allowed\nD.An activity identification number must be larger that that of any preceding activities\nE.Networks flow from left to right","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"See List on Page 161.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"16.________ activities must be completed immediately before a particular activity.\nA.Merge\nB.Burst\nC.Predecessor\nD.Successor\nE.Critical","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Which activities must be completed immediately before this activity? These activities are called predecessoractivities.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"17.________ activities are to be completed immediately following a particular activity.\nA.Merge\nB.Burst\nC.Predecessor\nD.Successor\nE.Critical","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Which activities must immediately follow this activity? These activities are called successor activities.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"18.The forward pass in project network calculations determines the\nA.Earliest time's activities can begin\nB.Earliest time's activities can be finished\nC.Duration of the project\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"The forward pass starts with the first project activity(ies) and traces each path (chain of sequential activities)through the network to the last project activity(ies).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"19.The backward pass in project network calculations determines the\nA.Latest time's activities can begin\nB.Earliest time's activities can be finished\nC.Critical path\nD.Both A and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"See list on Page 165.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"20.Which of the following correctly calculates the early finish for an activity?\nA.LS + DUR\nB.ES + DUR\nC.LF + DUR\nD.ES + SL\nE.LF + SL","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"The early finish for activity = (ES + DUR).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"21.Which of the following correctly calculates the late start for an activity?\nA.EF - DUR\nB.ES - DUR\nC.LF - DUR\nD.ES - SL\nE.LF - SLACK","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"You subtract activity times along each path starting with the project end activity (LF - DUR = LS).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"22.The amount of time an activity can be delayed and yet not delay the project is termed\nA.Total slack\nB.Free slack\nC.Critical float\nD.Float pad\nE.Slip pad","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Total slack tells us the amount of time an activity can be delayed and yet not delay the project. Stated differently,total slack is the amount of time an activity can exceed its early finish date without affecting the projectend date or an imposed completion date.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"23.Which of the following will correctly calculate the total slack in an activity?\nA.LS - ES\nB.LF - EF\nC.LS - LF\nD.LF - ES\nE.Both A and B are correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Total slack or float for an activity is simply the difference between the LS and ES (LS - ES = SL) or betweenLF and EF (LF - EF = SL).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"24.The laying pipe example in the text illustrates the concept of\nA.Laddering\nB.Hammock activities\nC.Critical path\nD.Concurrent engineering\nE.Forward pass","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The assumption that all immediate preceding activities must be 100 percent complete is too restrictive for somesituations found in practice. This restriction occurs most frequently when one activity overlaps the startof another and has a long duration. Under the standard finish-to-start relationship, when an activity hasa long duration and will delay the start of an activity immediately following it, the activity can be brokeninto segments and the network drawn using a laddering approach so the following activity can begin soonerand not delay the work.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"25.Using a special color copy machine for a tradeshow publication illustrates the concept of\nA.Laddering\nB.Hammock activities\nC.Critical path\nD.Concurrent engineering\nE.Forward pass","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Hammock activities are frequently used to identify the use of fixed resources or costs over a segment of theproject. Typical examples of hammock activities are inspection services, consultants, or construction managementservices. A hammock activity derives its duration from the time span between other activities. For example,a special color copy machine is needed for a segment of a tradeshow publication project. A hammock activitycan be used to indicate the need for this resource and to apply costs over this segment of the project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"26.If, for some reason, the project must be expedited to meet an earlier date, which of the following actions wouldthe project manager take first?\nA.Check to see which activities cost the least\nB.Check to see which activities have the longest duration\nC.Check to see which activities are on the critical path\nD.Check to see which activities have the most slack\nE.Check to see which activities have the highest risk","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"If for some reason the project must be expedited to meet an earlier date, it is possible to select those activities,or combination of activities, that will cost the least to shorten the project. Similarly, if the criticalpath is delayed and the time must be made up by shortening some activity or activities on the critical pathto make up any negative slack, it is possible to identify the activities on the critical path that cost theleast to shorten. If there are other paths with very little slack, it may be necessary to shorten activitieson those paths also.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"27.Typically an activity on a project network represents\nA.A single work package\nB.One or more tasks from a work package\nC.Several work packages\nD.A sub-deliverable\nE.A cost account","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"Work packages from the WBS are used to build the activities found in the project network.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"28.Project network logic errors include which of the following?\nA.Activities with less than 1 day duration\nB.Sequences such as \"if test successful build prototype, if failure redesign\"\nC.A sequence such as B succeeds A, C succeeds B, A succeeds C\nD.Both B and C are network logic errors\nE.A, B, and C are all network logic errors","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"One rule is that conditional statements such as \"if test successful build proto, if failure redesign\" are notpermitted. Another rule that defeats the project network and computation process is looping. Looping is anattempt by the planner to return to an earlier activity.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"29.Which company utilized concurrent engineering to design a new line of cars and in the process completed its developmentsix months ahead of schedule?\nA.General Motors\nB.Chrysler\nC.Ford\nD.Nissan\nE.Toyota","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"The traditional chainlike sequence of finish-to-start relationships is replaced by a series of start-to-startlag relationships as soon as meaningful work can be initiated for the next phase. Figure 6.17 summarizesthe dramatic gains in time to market achieved by this approach. For example, this approach was used by ChryslerCorporation to design its new line of SC cars including the popular Neon sedan.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"30.The minimum amount of time a dependent activity must be delayed to begin or end is referred to as:\nA.Hammock\nB.Laddering\nC.Lag\nD.Cushion\nE.Buffer","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"A lag is the minimum amount of time a dependent activity must be delayed to begin or end.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"31.The requirement for a freshly poured foundation to cure before beginning construction is an example of whichof the following type of lag?\nA.Start to Start\nB.Start to Finish\nC.Finish to Finish\nD.Finish to Start\nE.Any of these could be correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"There are situations in which the next activity in a sequence must be delayed even when the preceding activityis complete. For example, removing concrete forms cannot begin until the poured cement has cured for twotime units.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"32.Concurrent engineering is a good example of good use of\nA.Start to Start lags\nB.Start to Finish lags\nC.Finish to Finish lags\nD.Finish to Start lags\nE.Any of these could be correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Concurrent Engineering, basically breaks activities into smaller segments so that work can be done in paralleland the project expedited. Start-to-start relationships can depict the concurrent engineering conditionsand reduce network detail.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"33.If testing cannot be completed any earlier than four days after the prototype is built, which of the followingtype of lag exists?\nA.Start to Start\nB.Start to Finish\nC.Finish to Finish\nD.Finish to Start\nE.Any of these could be correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The finish of one activity depends on the finish of another activity. For example, testing cannot be completedany earlier than four days after the prototype is complete.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"34.Which of the following represents an activity on an AOA project network?\nA.An arrow\nB.A line\nC.A node\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The activity-on-arrow (AOA) uses an arrow to depict an activity.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"35.Nodes on an AON project network represent:\nA.An activity\nB.An event\nC.Responsibility\nD.Both B and C are correct\nE.Both A and B are correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The activity-on- node (AON) uses a node to depict an activity.Fill in the Blank Questions","difficulty":"Fill in the Blank Questions"},{"question":"36.A(n) ________ is an element in the project that consumes time.","type":"fill-in","answer":"activity","help":"An activity is an element of the project that requires time. It may or may not require resources.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"37.The activity time estimates used to build a project network are derived from ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"work packages","help":"A work package is defined independently of other work packages, has definite start and finish points, requiresspecific resources, includes technical specifications, and has cost estimates for the package.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"38.A ________ is an activity that has more than one predecessor.","type":"fill-in","answer":"merge activity","help":"Merge activity is an activity that has more than one activity immediately preceding it (more than one dependencyarrow flowing to it).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"39.In a ________ the delaying of any activity will delay the completion of the project by the same amount.","type":"fill-in","answer":"critical path","help":"Critical path means the path(s) with the longest duration through the network; if an activity on the path isdelayed, the project is delayed the same amount of time.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"40.Activities that can take place at the same time if the manager wishes them to are called ________.","type":"fill-in","answer":"parallel activities","help":"Parallel activities are activities that can take place at the same time, if the manager wishes. However, themanager may choose to have parallel activities not occur simultaneously.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"41.A (n) ________ represents a point in time when an activity is started or completed and does not consume time.","type":"fill-in","answer":"event","help":"Event is used to represent a point in time when an activity is started or completed. It does not consume time.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"42.A (n) ________ has more than one successor activity.","type":"fill-in","answer":"burst activity","help":"Burst activity has more than one activity immediately following it (more than one dependency arrow flowing fromit).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"43.The ________ approach to creating project networks has come to dominate most projects.\nAON or activity-on-node","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"AON or activity-on-node","help":"In practice, the activity-on-node (AON) method has come to dominate most projects.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"44.In a project network, ________ (recycling through a set of activities) is not permitted.","type":"fill-in","answer":"looping","help":"Looping is not allowed (in other words, recycling through a set of activities cannot take place).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"45.In a project network, ________ indicate precedence and flow.","type":"fill-in","answer":"arrows","help":"The wide availability of personal computers and graphics programs has served as an impetus for use of the activity-on-node(AON) method (sometimes called the precedence diagram method). The dependencies among activities are depictedby arrows between the rectangles (boxes) on the AON network. The arrows indicate how the activities are relatedand the sequence in which things must be accomplished.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"46.The ________ method for creating project networks is sometimes called the Precedence Diagram Method.\nAON or activity-on-node","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"AON or activity-on-node","help":"The wide availability of personal computers and graphics programs has served as an impetus for use of the activity-on-node(AON) method (sometimes called the precedence diagram method).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"47.Activities that must occur immediately before a given activity are called ________ activities.","type":"fill-in","answer":"predecessor","help":"Activities that must be completed immediately before an activity are called predecessor activities.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"48.Activities that must immediately follow a given activity are called ________ activities.","type":"fill-in","answer":"successor","help":"Activities that must immediately follow an activity are called successor activities.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"49.Activities that can occur while an activity is taking place are called ________ activities.","type":"fill-in","answer":"parallel or concurrent","help":"Activities that can occur while an activity is taking place is known as a concurrent or parallel relationship.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"50.The ________ calculates the earliest times that activities can be started or finished.","type":"fill-in","answer":"forward pass","help":"Forward Pass describes how soon can the activity start? (early start—ES) and how soon can the activity finish?(early finish—EF).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"51.The ________ calculates the critical path and determines how long an activity can be delayed without delayingthe project.","type":"fill-in","answer":"backward pass","help":"The backwards pass which activities represent the critical path (CP). This is the longest path in the networkwhich, when delayed, will delay the project and how long can the activity be delayed? (slack or float—SL).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"52.An activity is on the critical path if its ________ is the lowest in the network.","type":"fill-in","answer":"total slack","help":"Total slack tells us the amount of time an activity can be delayed and yet not delay the project. Stated differently,total slack is the amount of time an activity can exceed its early finish date without affecting the projectend date or an imposed completion date.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"53.________ can never be negative and applies only to the last activity in a single chain of activities.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Free slack","help":"Free slack is the amount of time and activity can be delayed without delaying any immediately following (successor)activity. Or, free slack is the amount of time an activity can exceed its early finish date without affectingthe early start date of any successor(s). Free slack can never be negative.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"54.A(n) ________ is the minimum amount of time a dependent activity must be delayed to begin or end.","type":"fill-in","answer":"lag","help":"A lag is the minimum amount of time a dependent activity must be delayed to begin or end.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"55.In the ________ technique, an activity with a long duration is broken into smaller segments so that the followingactivities can begin sooner.","type":"fill-in","answer":"laddering","help":"The assumption that all immediate preceding activities must be 100 percent complete is too restrictive for somesituations found in practice. This restriction occurs most frequently when one activity overlaps the startof another and has a long duration. Under the standard finish-to-start relationship, when an activity hasa long duration and will delay the start of an activity immediately following it, the activity can be brokeninto segments and the network drawn using a laddering approach so the following activity can begin soonerand not delay the work.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"56.____________ is defined as the difference between the EF of an activity and the ES of the activity that followsit.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Free Slack (Float)","help":"See Figure 6.9 on Page 172.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"57.___________ reflects the likelihood the original critical path(s) will change once the project is initiated.","type":"fill-in","answer":"Sensitivity","help":"Sensitivity reflects the likelihood the original critical path(s) will change once the project is initiated.Sensitivity is a function of the number of critical or near-critical paths.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"58.A ____________ lag exists if debug cannot begin until two days after coding has started and that coding mustbe completed four days before debug can be completed.","type":"fill-in","answer":"combination","help":"More than one lag relationship can be attached to an activity. These relationships are usually start-to-startand finish-to-finish combinations tied to two activities. For example, debug cannot begin until two timeunits after coding has started. Coding must be finished four days before debug can be finished (see Figure6.20 on page 181).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"59.The _________ lag is the most typical type of lag that is encountered in developing networks.","type":"fill-in","answer":"finish to start","help":"The finish-to-start relationship represents the typical, generic network However, there are situations in whichthe next activity in a sequence must be delayed even when the preceding activity is complete.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"60.A __________ activity is frequently used to identify the use of fixed resources or costs over a segment of theproject.","type":"fill-in","answer":"hammock","help":"Hammock activities are frequently used to identify the use of fixed resources or costs over a segment of theproject. Typical examples of hammock activities are inspection services, consultants, or construction managementservices. A hammock activity derives its duration from the time span between other activities. For example,a special color copy machine is needed for a segment of a tradeshow publication project. A hammock activitycan be used to indicate the need for this resource and to apply costs over this segment of the project.True / False Questions","difficulty":"True / False Questions"},{"question":"61.An activity includes only one work package.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Activities usually represent one or more tasks from a work package.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"62.Project networks are built using nodes and arrows.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The two approaches used to develop project networks are known as activity-on-node (AON) and activity-on-arrow(AOA). Both methods use two building blocks—the arrow and the node.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"63.The WBS identifies dependencies, the sequencing of activities, and the timing of activities.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Networks provide the project schedule by identifying dependencies, sequencing, and timing of activities, whichthe WBS is not designed to do.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"64.The critical path is the shortest path through a network and indicates activities that cannot be delayed withoutdelaying the project.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Critical path means the path(s) with the longest duration through the network; if an activity on the path isdelayed, the project is delayed the same amount of time.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"65.An activity is an element of the project that always requires time but may or may not require resources.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"An activity is an element of the project that requires time. It may or may not require resources.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"66.The two approaches used to develop project networks are AOA and AON.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The two approaches used to develop project networks are known as activity-on-node (AON) and activity-on-arrow(AOA).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"67.In an AOA network an activity is represented by a box.Refer to Appendix 6.1","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The activity-on-arrow (AOA) approach also uses the arrow and node as network building blocks. However, in thisapproach the arrow represents an individual project activity that requires time. The length and slope ofthe arrow have no significance. The node represents an event; it is usually presented as a small circle.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"68.In developing a project network, each activity should have a unique identification number that is smaller thanthe identification numbers of activities that follow it.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Each activity should have a unique identification number. And that activity identification number must be largerthan that of any activities that precede it.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"69.In developing a project network, neither looping statements nor conditional statements are permitted.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Looping is not allowed (in other words, recycling through a set of activities cannot take place). Also Conditionalif not, do nothing).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"70.Experience suggests that when there are multiple starts, a common start node should not be used to indicate aclear project beginning on the network. Similarly, a single project end node can be used to indicate a clearending.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Experience suggests that when there are multiple starts, a common start node can be used to indicate a clearproject beginning on the network. Similarly, a single project end node can be used to indicate a clear ending.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"71.Burst activities have more than one activity immediately following it (more than one dependency arrow flowingfrom it).","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Burst activities have more than one activity immediately following it (more than one dependency arrow flowingfrom it).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"72.It is acceptable for arrows to cross one another in a network diagram.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Arrows on networks indicate precedence and flow. Arrows can cross over each other.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"73.The forward pass through a project network determines the critical path.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The forward pass starts with the first project activity(ies) and traces each path (chain of sequential activities)through the network to the last project activity(ies). The forward pass assumes every activity will startthe instant in time when the last of its predecessors is finished.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"74.The backward pass though a project network determines how long an activity can be delayed without impacting thecompletion date of the project.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"The backwards pass which activities represent the critical path (CP). This is the longest path in the networkwhich, when delayed, will delay the project and how long can the activity be delayed (slack or float—SL).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"75.Different activities along the same path can have different total slack.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"If slack of one activity in a path is used, the ES for all activities that follow in the chain will be delayedand their slack reduced. Use of total slack must be coordinated with all participants in the activities thatfollow in the chain.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"76.By definition, the critical path always has zero slack.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"The critical path follows activity start and finish constraints that occur due to the use of the additional relationshipsavailable and the imposed lags.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"77.It is possible to have more than one critical path at the same time.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Critical path means the path(s) with the longest duration through the network; if an activity on the path isdelayed, the project is delayed the same amount of time.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"78.Free slack applies to an entire project network.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"Free slack is the amount of time and activity can be delayed without delaying any immediately following (successor)activity. Or, free slack is the amount of time an activity can exceed its early finish date without affectingthe early start date of any successor(s).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"79.Gantt charts are popular because they represent an easy-to-understand, clear picture on a time-scaled horizon.Refer to Figure 6.12","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"See Figure 6.12 on Page 176.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"80.Lags are used to break larger activities into smaller segments so that activities that follow can be startedearlier.","type":"boolean","answer":"FALSE","help":"When activities of long duration delay the start or finish of successor activities, the network designer normallybreaks the activity into smaller activities to avoid the long delay of the successor activity. Use of lagscan avoid such delays and reduce network detail.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"81.Only activities that occur at the end of a chain of activities can have free slack.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Free slack occurs at the last activity in a chain of activities. In many situations the \"chain\" can have onlyone link.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"82.Lags can be use to constrain the start and finish of an activity.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Lags can be used to constrain the start and finish of an activity.Short Answer Questions","difficulty":"Short Answer Questions"},{"question":"83.Identify and discuss the two major reasons for the integration of work packages into the project network failingin actual practice.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. different people are used to define work packages and the network, and 2. the WBS is poorly constructed andnot deliverable/output oriented.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"84.What are the two approaches used to develop project networks and identify the differences between them?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. activity-on-node; where nodes depict activities and the arrows show flow and dependencies and 2. activity-on-arrow;where nodes represent events and achievement of the activities is represented by the arrow connecting thenodes.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"85.What are the eight rules to follow in developing project networks?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. flow left to right, 2. activities cannot begin until all predecessors have been completed, 3. arrows indicateprecedence and flow, 4. each activity should have a unique identification number, 5. activity ID numbersmust be larger than preceding ID number, 6. looping is not permitted, 7. conditional statements are not permitted,and 8. create a common start node for multiple start activities.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"86.In the network computation process what is a forward pass and what three things does it determine?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Starting with the first activity, each path is traced forward through the network, adding times until the endof the project. This determines 1. how soon each activity can start, 2. how soon each activity can finish,and 3. how soon the entire project can be completed.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"87.In the network computation process what is a backward pass and what four things does it determine?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Starting with the last activity, each path is traced backward through the network, subtracting times until thebeginning of the project. This determines 1. how late each activity can start, 2. how late each activitycan finish, 3. the critical path, and 4. how long can each activity be delayed without changing the completiondate.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"88.What is total slack and how do you determine it?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Slack is the amount of time specific activities can be delayed without causing the project to miss its completiondate. It is calculated by subtracting the Early Start date from the Late Start date (SL = LS-ES) or subtractingthe Early Finish date from the Late Finish date (SL = LF-EF).","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"89.What is a Gantt chart and what advantages does it have over project networks?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Gantt charts are bar charts where activities are displayed as bars on a horizontal time-scale. They are easy-to-readand provide a clear overview of the project schedule and progress against that schedule.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"90.What is the laddering approach to project networks and why would you use this approach?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"In laddering, lengthy activities are segmented into small pieces so that successor activities can begin priorto the completion of the initial activity. This effectively reduces the overall project time. The text useda laying pipeline example to illustrate.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"91.What is a lag and why would you need to use one?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"A lag is the minimum amount of time a dependent activity must be delayed to begin or end. They occur during ladderingand avoid delays and they are also used to constraint the start and finish of an activity.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"92.What is a hammock activity and give an example?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"A hammock activity identifies the use of a resource over a segment of the project. Thus its duration is determinedby the duration of other activities. The example used in the text was for a color copier during specificphases of a project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"93.What is the Concurrent Engineering Approach and why should project managers be aware of it?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The chainlike sequence of finish-to-start relationships is replaced by a series of start-to-start lag relationshipsas soon as meaningful work can be initiated for the next phase. The resulting overlap of tasks slightly increasesrisk but results in a much shorter schedule.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"94.Identify and briefly describe the four types of lags giving an example for each type.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Finish-to-Start, 2. Start-to-Start, 3. Finish-to-Finish, 4. Start-to-Finish.6-1","difficulty":"1"}]